The City of Water, Water Seven
Luffy and Robin needed some recovery time,
so the Going Merry dropped anchor...
off the uninhabited island for four days.
After that, we set sail.
This is the third morning
since we resumed our voyage.
Today's weather is a gorgeous mix of spring,
peppered with occasional bouts of summer.
What a beautiful day!
Nami-swan!
I made potato paille.
Mademoiselle, if you would.
Mmm, it's delicious!
I'm overjoyed!
Keep it down! I'm trying to sleep!
Yeah, yeah, sorry
about that, cactus head.
What'd you say, dartboard brows?!
Dar– What'd you
just say, you bastard?!
Dartboard brows.
Luffy! Yeah! Luffy! All right!
Luffy! Yeah! Luffy!
It's about time!
Luffy!
My frozen-self reenactment.
Geez. I can't believe he's doing
that after he got frozen and almost died.
– Was it close?
– You nailed it! That was exactly it, Luffy!
Clean that up good, okay, Luffy?!
Hm? What're you eating, Nami?
It's paille, a potato dish.
Potato, huh? I'm hungry too. Hey, Sanji!
Just how much sleep do
you need anyway?!
How much sleep I need is my business!
If you wanna have a go, then bring it on!
They said this is called paille. It's good!
What's a paille?
It's the tail meat of a
huge monster named Paille.
I killed it. It was
at least 100 meters high.
100 meters?! That's amazing, Usopp!
Hmm, piece of cake.
I did it before breakfast.
What? You got up
early and killed it?
Chopper, say my name.
What? That's, of course, C-Captain...
That's right! My name is...
Captain... Usopp–
Robin!
Hey! Robin-chwan !
How are you feeling?
Are you chilly?
I'm feeling a lot better,
all thanks to an amazing doctor.
Oh, being called an amazing doctor
won't make me feel happy or anything, you jerk.
– He sure does look happy.
– Yeah.
Take it easy, Robin.
Don't feel pressured
just because Luffy is up and about,
despite having experienced the same thing as you.
You can take your time
and rest, you know.
– Yay!
– That's not a compliment!
Robin-chan ! Shall I make
something to warm you up?
How's your appetite?
Well then, may I have some coffee?
All right! It'd be my pleasure!
Hm?
What's that?
Anyway, this paille thing is so good,
we can't stop eating it.
Yeah, it's yummy!
Hey, if we sell this stuff,
wouldn't it rake in the dough?
Hey, Luffy!
A-A frog is doing the front crawl!
What?!
It went to your side,
so take a look!
– Is that true?
– A frog? Like, a real frog?
Hey, Luffy, are you seriously taking stock
in what ol' King Stupid said?
For starters, it's impossible for frogs
to do the front cra– It's doing it!
A-A frog is doing the front crawl!
– Let's follow it, guys!
– Yeah!
Furl the sail! Stand by the oars!
Turn the ship to 2 o'clock!
– Yeah!
– Faster!
I can't explain it, but I
get the feeling we need to chase it!
Sorry to keep you waiting, mademoiselles.
What?
What?! What happened?!
It feels like the ship changed course.
Hey, you guys! Who said you could
change course without consulting me?!
Hey, Nami, you've got to hear this!
We found a huge frog
with scars all over its body!
What the heck?
The plan's to roast it whole and eat it!
You're gonna eat it?!
Hey, you're right.
Hm? A lighthouse?
Why is there a lighthouse in a place like this?
Is anyone even there?
Wh-What do you see?
Is it an island?
No, it's a lighthouse. The log pose
wouldn't point to a place like this.
And the frog?
Tell us where the frog swam to!
Not a chance!
The frog is headed to the lighthouse.
What?
To cook frogs, first remove the slime using white wine,
then dust them in flour
and fry them till crisp.
Hey, Sanji-kun!
If our captain says we're going,
what choice do we have but to go?
Robin!
All right! Full speed ahead!
Yeah!
How are you all in agreement?!
Heave-ho! Heave-ho! Heave-ho!
It's flying!
Don't let it get away! Move
ahead of it and block its course!
Heave-ho! Heave-ho! Heave-ho!
We ran aground on something!
Ahh, Nami-san, Robin-chan,
are you two okay?
Yeah, luckily.
I'm okay.
Good. Hm?
What? What's that sound?
What? What's going on?
Is this...? Don't tell me...
Why? In a place like this?!
Ow, ow, ow!
Go back! Go back!
Rotate 180 degrees!
What the hell is this?!
Wh-Wh-What in the world
is this hulking piece of iron?!
A ship?
Not possible! Something shaped
like this isn't seaworthy!
Hey, frog! Run! What're you doing?!
Ahhh! It got run over!
The ship was puffing out smoke!
Pirates?
Grandma! Grandma! Pirates are here!
What?! Is that so, Chimney?!
Okay then, bring
the transponder snail to me!
Okay!
This is a problem.
Someone came out of the building.
They're gonna call for help.
Here it is, Grandma!
Err, hello?
Let's see. What was it? I forgot.
She's wasted?!
Oh? Paille, huh?
It goes good with booze.
Whoa! This is tasty!
I'm Chimney. This is our cat, Gonbe,
Chimney
Kokoro's Grandchild
Gonbe
A Cat (Actually a Rabbit)
and Grandma Kokoro.
Stationmaster Kokoro
Shift Station
You guys aren't train robbers, are you?
I'm Luffy. I'm the man
who'll be king of the pirates.
– Really?!
– Yeah.
What a funny guy.
Say, Chimney, that thing
is a steamship, right?
But with a shape like that,
there's no way it could ever sail.
You've never seen anything
like it, have you?
You won't find its equal anywhere else in the world.
It's a sea train called
the Puffing Tom.
Puffing Tom?
Its steam engine turns paddlewheels
while it travels along the sea railway.
Railway?
That's right. It floats
just below the water's surface.
The train travels
the same route every day,
taking passengers
from one island to another.
It hauls ships and delivers the mail as well.
She's right. There really is a railway.
Yep! The rails are marked off,
and there's even a signal.
It's dangerous to go
inside the barrier like that!
Dangerous or not,
that guy wouldn't understand, right?
It wasn't nice to send him flying.
We saw him first.
What? "That guy"?
Are you talking about Yokozuna?
Yep, that front crawl frog.
Yokozuna wouldn't die from that.
He's the source of all our
headaches here at Shift Station.
He loves testing his strength
by trying to defeat the sea train.
He'll be back.
Testing his strength? Oh!
That's why he stood his ground, huh?
He's got guts.
Give me a break!
He's a royal pain!
The grill also keeps getting broken!
Every time he shows up,
the passengers freak out!
I think I get the big picture.
Okay, then!
I won't eat him!
I can't eat a fighter!
Eating a frog should never
have entered your head!
So, you guys headed somewhere?
If you're gonna take
the sea train from here, there's:
St. Poplar, Town of the Spring Queen;
Pucci, the Gourmet Town;
and San Faldo, the Carnival Town!
They're all fun places.
If you work for the government,
you'd take a separate, special train.
Okay, we'll pick the Gourmet Town.
No, we won't!
Since we've got our own ship,
we won't need the train.
We're gonna follow our log.
Oh? Where's it pointing?
East of here.
Indeed? Then it must be Water Seven.
The train you saw earlier came
from that island's Blue Station.
It's called the City of Water.
It's a fantastic place.
What's more, the city is known far and wide
for its shipbuilding industry.
Their technology is unrivaled the world over!
Even the World Government favors
the ships built there! Amazing, right?
No way! Then there's gotta be
some amazing shipwrights, right?!
Not just "some"! It's a crossroads
of the world's best shipwrights!
Usopp!
Yeah!
All right! I've decided!
We're gonna go there and
get a shipwright to join our crew for sure!
Oh, is that right?
Then hold on a sec.
Up I go.
– What's she up to?
– Beats me.
Well, then. Here's a basic map
of the island and a letter of introduction.
Hand this to a guy named Iceburg
and ask him to take good care of your ship.
Water Seven is a big place.
Don't get lost.
Whoa!
You have a heart of gold, Kokoro-san ! So kind!
In a bit, we're gonna go back to Water Seven too.
Oh, true! If we meet again,
first round's on me at my favorite bar.
Okay! I hope we see you guys again!
At Water Seven, it'll take about a week
for the log to register. Kick back and relax.
Yeah! Thanks!
All right, guys!
Get ready to set sail!
– Yeah!
– Well then, we're off!
Thanks for all your help,
Kokoro-san ! Chimney!
Be careful!
Watch out for the government people!
Yahoo! Let's go!
To the city of meat! Yahoo!
Were you even listening?
Mmm. What a nice breeze!
Perhaps we'll make it to the
City of Water sooner than expected.
I hope so.
Luffy, leave scouting out the shipwright to me.
I'll make sure she's incredibly attractive.
Are you a moron?!
This is a shipwright we're talking about!
It's gotta be a big guy the size of
a mountain! Five meters tall!
But if he's too big,
he might not fit on this ship.
All that matters is
that he's skilled, right?
The real issue is finding someone crazy enough...
to agree to sailing on a pirate ship.
I can't wait!
We're gonna make a new friend!
We were lucky to stop at the station first,
since they drew a map for us.
If we go to the place on the map
and find that Iceburg guy...
Around here
Water 7
Makes sense...
Around here
Water 7
This tells me nothing!
Whoa! This is like something
Luffy would draw.
Here. We need to keep an eye out
for a guy like this.
Shipwright
meters
If there was a guy like that, I'd run.
Same here. I'd hop on the next ship
and hightail it out to sea.
But with this guy looking like an octopus,
he might chase me out to the open water.
What the hell are you
guys going on about?!
Come here, guys!
You each get an allowance
to last you the week we're ashore.
Seriously?! Yaay! I'm first!
Whoa! That's generous!
Hey! Get in line!
Allowance! Allowance! Allowance!
You doin' okay, Usopp?
This tinplate patchwork brings back
memories of battles and adventure.
I can't help but gush over the thought
of her upcoming repairs.
– I get it, but...
– Hm?
our journey, especially since
entering the Grand Line,
has taken quite a toll on the Merry.
The deck creaks,
and the hull is pretty leaky.
If nothing's done, that'll be it
for both the ship and us.
Yeah, but we're filthy rich now.
We can make her good as new!
No, even better than that!
Well, then let's get more cannons!
And we'll put a bronze statue on the deck!
Hey, is that it?
Hm?
It's the island! We can see the island!
Okay, guys! Row!
We've got a decent tailwind.
Don't make us waste our energy!
How wonderful!
It's incredible!
Water Seven
"The City of Water"
Grand Line
Water Seven
"The City of Water"
Grand Line
What is this place?!
The fountain's enormous!
Unbelievable! An actual industrial city!
That's why it has the sea train.
The building just ahead must be the station.
It says Blue Station.
I wonder where we dock.
It must be in town.
– Hey, you there!
– Hm?
It's not okay for you pirates
to openly sail out front!
Go around that way
to the backstreets!
Okay! Thanks!
Whoa, this is amazing!
A city on the water?!
Wow! This place is cool!
Such a pretty city!
But the city is flooded.
The houses are submerged in the sea.
Look again. The city was designed
with its base underwater.
– Huh?
– You can see the foundation underneath.
You're right! The pillars
raise up the structures!
I see. That's why it's called
the City of Water, huh?
Hey, hurry up and dock the ship!
Hm?
Hey, hey, you guys!
Pirate ships should steer clear of this area!
What'd you come here for?!
To plunder?!
No! We wanna get our ship repaired!
Is it normal for people to straight up
ask if we're here to plunder?
In that case, there's a cape just ahead,
so anchor your ship there for now!
Okay!
Thanks!
Again?
What'd you expect?
We're pirates, after all.
This area should be okay,
don't you think?
It sure is bleak though.
All right, then! Furl the sail!
What're you doing?!
Nothing! All I did was pull the rope!
You're kidding me!
The Going Merry is already this rickety?
Say, did you notice the people
on this island aren't too scared of pirates?
Probably because pirates are just
another customer for their shipyards.
Less talking! More fixing!
Could it be that their sentries are strong enough...
to deal with pirates who cause a ruckus?
They probably do,
considering the size of the city.
Is that so?! Then what're
we gonna do? This is bad.
Why would it be bad?
We're customers.
Y-You think so?
Okay, then! See you later!
Wait, Luffy! Usopp!
You two, come with me.
Hm?
Where to?
First, we'll take Kokoro-san's
letter of introduction...
and go find the man named Iceburg.
We'll ask him
to facilitate the ship's repair.
Then we gotta find a place
where we can cash in our gold.
If that's it, then okay!
Onward! To the City of Water!
You're forgetting the gold.
Ah!
Hey! There're pirates making a scene at Dock One!
What?! For real?!
We'd better hurry and see!
I don't understand what you're talkin' about.
A Dockyard
Water Seven
Well, actually,
Dock One
I thought about it carefully.
Captain Mikazuki
Big Helmet Pirates
Bounty: 36 Million Belly
Captain Mikazuki
Big Helmet Pirates
Bounty: 36 Million Belly
I thought about it really carefully.
While it's true that you guys repaired our ship,
I couldn't help but notice
the invoice was a bit too high.
You're interruptin' our work.
So, I decided not to pay
—not one belly.
Thanks for the flawless repairs!
Plus, it's all free!
Um, Kalifa, what's going on over there?
Yes, Iceburg-san.
They're Dock One customers.
Now that the work has been completed,
they're saying they won't pay.
That's sexual harassment.
Um, that is sexual harassment.
Sir, you'd be wise not
to provoke craftsmen like that.
C-Captain!
Captain!
Oops, pardon me.
You son of a bitch!
You should watch where you're going!
Oh, pardon me.
Y-You bastards! Are you picking a fight?!
Who in the hell do you think we are?!
Hey, have you test-fired the cannon?
Oh. Not yet, sir.
Dammit! Who the hell are you guys?!
You won't get away with this!
Galley-La Company
A Shipbuilding Firm, Water Seven
(Purveyors to the World Government)
Galley-La Company
A Shipbuilding Firm, Water Seven
(Purveyors to the World Government)
Pirate ways don't go over so well...
on craftsmen's turf, you hear?
Why don't we go to the exchange shop first?
Why? Let's go to the shipyard.
But we can't just walk around the island
with this much gold. It puts me on edge.
Isn't the value the same
even after it's exchanged?
Even so, the size of our load
might attract attention, don't you think?
What if we run into thieves?
But we are thieves!
He's got a point. Trading it in for bills
would mean we each hold on to some of it.
Hey, what's with that remark?
Do you have a problem
if I'm the only one carrying it?
Yeah. You might drop
it somewhere or lose it.
Yeah, he would.
This is Luffy we're talking about.
What?! Guys!
Don't you trust me?!
– Nope!
– Ah... Ahh... Ahh... That really hurts!
You've really done it this ti– Hm?
Is this the only entrance to the city?
A rental bull shop?
What's that?
What do they rent out?
What's a "bull"?
Beats me. Bulldogs?
Can't be, right?
Excuse me!
We'd like to rent your bull!
Ask what it is first!
Welcome! You wanna rent bulls, right?
How many people?
Three!
What kind of bulls would you like?
There're three ranks:
yagara, rabuka, and king.
Well, for the three of you,
two yagara would probably do.
Okay! Please roast 'em
till they're nice and tasty!
You're making things weird, you weirdo!
Oh? You followed a log to get here?
– Yep.
– That's quite the undertaking, you guys.
Then you had no idea
what bulls were, did you?
– Right.
– Well, to make a long story short, those are bulls.
They're yagara bulls.
They're everywhere in town.
In this area, there's a fish called a yagara
that swims with its head out.
This is the City of Water.
There're more canals than walkways.
So the residents here find bulls
to be a necessary form of transportation.
It's the same when you
go sightseeing on this island.
That fish is pulling a boat?
Actually, rather than pulling,
they're letting people ride on their back.
Well, it's like horseback riding
or riding in a carriage on land.
You see the fish pen there?
Well, try and ride on one. It's comfortable.
For two of the two-passenger yagara bulls,
it's 2,000 belly, all told.
Wow, they're cute!
It's a fish that looks like a horse.
You jerk! What'd you do that for?!
Oh? He must like you.
Let's get that one for you.
Can he carry heavy stuff okay?
Their power is incredible! They're often
used when moving household goods.
That bag, huh? Whatcha got in there?
Gold.
Good one!
Whatever it is, they can handle it.
– See?
– Whoa! Share the wealth!
No way!
This old guy wears his heart on his sleeve.
And you! Don't show it off
to others so casually!
Why's that?
It's no big deal.
My, my, what a surprise.
Well, then. It'll be a million belly
for two yagara bulls.
Hey, the price went up, pops.
Incidentally, are there any
exchange shops around here?
Yeah, there are, but
with that amount of gold,
the shops around here probably
wouldn't have enough money.
You should go to the downtown area
of Shipyard Island.
The downtown area of Shipyard Island?
Where's that?
In that direction.
Take this with you.
A map?
This'll be helpful! Thanks!
Pops, is the shipyard that way, too?
Yeah. The world's number one shipyard!
That's perfect. Once we get the money,
we'll be real close to the shipyard.
Yeah. We can finally have
the Going Merry repaired!
And we'll find a shipwright, too!
I'm getting excited!
– Well, then.
– Shall we?
All right! Go, yagara!
Thanks for your business! Be careful!
Full speed to the shipyard!
Yahoo!
Editing:
Galaxy 9000
Timing:
PhosCity
Quality Control:
Galaxy 9000,
Pepperjack,
Zenef
Soundtracking:
Halee
Graphics:
Datenshi
Karaoke:
KaitouYahiko
Translation:
Crunchyroll,
Gaijin